{"Topic": "Agriculture", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Jute cultivation in India is concentrated in the delta area of which of the following rivers?", "op1": "Ganga", "op2": "Mahanadi", "op3": "Brahamputra", "op4": "Godavari", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the largest irrigation canal in India?", "op1": "Buckingham Canal", "op2": "Sirhind Canal", "op3": "Indira Gandhi Canal", "op4": "Sutlej Yamuna Link Canal", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following is the correct sequence in the decreasing order of production (in million tonnes) of the given foodgrains in India?", "op1": "Wheat - Rice - Pulses - Coarse cereals", "op2": "Rice - Wheat - Pulses - Coarse cereals", "op3": "Wheat - Rice - Coarse cereals - Pulses", "op4": "Rice - Wheat - Coarse cereals - Pulses", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The eyes of potato are useful for", "op1": "Nutrition", "op2": "Respiration", "op3": "Vegetative Propagation", "op4": "Protection from predators", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What is Slash and Burn Agriculture?", "op1": "method of sugarcane cultivation", "op2": "process of deforestation", "op3": "agriculture without irrigation", "op4": "jhum cultivation", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Rotation of crops means", "op1": "growing of different crops in the same area in sequential seasons.", "op2": "shifting of area of same crops.", "op3": "growing two or more crops simultaneously to increase productivity.", "op4": "alternating crops with fruits over a period of years.", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The nitrogen present in the atmosphere is", "op1": "of no use to plants", "op2": "injurious to plants", "op3": "directly utilized by plants", "op4": "utilized through micro-organisms", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which is the largest cotton growing State in India?", "op1": "Maharashtra", "op2": "Madhya Pradesh", "op3": "Andhra Pradesh", "op4": "Gujarat", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The variety of coffee largely grown in India is -", "op1": "Old Chicks", "op2": "Coorgs", "op3": "Arabica", "op4": "Kents", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Under which plan did the Government introduce an agricultural strategy which gave rise to Green Revolution?", "op1": "Third Five-Year Plan (FYP)", "op2": "Fourth FYP", "op3": "Fifth FYP", "op4": "Second FYP", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Laterite soil develops as a result of-", "op1": "Deposits of alluvial", "op2": "Deposition of loess", "op3": "Leaching of sedimentary rocks", "op4": "Wind-blown dust", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What kind of soil is treated with gypsum to make it suitable for cropping?", "op1": "Aluvial", "op2": "Acidic", "op3": "Water-logged", "op4": "Soil with excessive clay content", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The United Nations General Assembly has declared 2013 as the International Year of ____", "op1": "Quinoa", "op2": "Buckwheat", "op3": "Rice", "op4": "Jatropha", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which one of the following is known as a pseudocereal?", "op1": "Wheat", "op2": "Quinoa", "op3": "Horse gram", "op4": "Barley", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Besides Rabi and Kharif, which is the third crop season in India?", "op1": "Zaid", "op2": "Barsati", "op3": "Sharad", "op4": "Jhum", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Kharif crops are harvested in -", "op1": "June - July", "op2": "October - November", "op3": "May - June", "op4": "March - April", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one among the following agricultural crops/groups of crops may be grown in abundant in lowlands and river deltas of fertile alluvial soil where there is high summer temperature and rainfall varies\u2019 from 180  cm  to  250  cm?", "op1": "Wheat and sugarcane", "op2": "Cotton", "op3": "Maize and coarse crops", "op4": "Rice, jute and tea", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following crops would be preferred for sowing in order to enrich the soil with nitrogen?", "op1": "Wheat", "op2": "Mustard", "op3": "Sunflower", "op4": "Gram", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "For which of the following is black soil not very suitable?", "op1": "Cotton", "op2": "Wheat", "op3": "Ground nut", "op4": "Potato", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Extensive areas of grape cultivation in France are especially called", "op1": "Wine cellars", "op2": "Grape fields", "op3": "Grape farms", "op4": "Vineyards", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "To which group does the black cotton soil of India belong?", "op1": "Laterite", "op2": "Podzol", "op3": "Chernozem", "op4": "Sierozem", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is a cash crop in India?", "op1": "Rice", "op2": "Wheat", "op3": "Sugarcane", "op4": "Jowar", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is a salt tolerant rice variety grown in water-logged coastal regions of Kerala?", "op1": "Navara", "op2": "Pokkali", "op3": "Ponni", "op4": "Samba", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is grown mainly on mountain slopes ?", "op1": "Paddy", "op2": "Tea", "op3": "Groundnut", "op4": "Potato", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which one of the following is not a nitrogenous fertilizer ?", "op1": "KCl", "op2": "CaCN2", "op3": "NH4NO3", "op4": "Urea", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which acid is used in the production of fertilizers?", "op1": "Nitric Acid", "op2": "Hydrochloric Acid", "op3": "Sulphuric Acid", "op4": "Carbonic Acid", "Answer": 4}]}